

I'm Abdullah Omer,

- Developed several robust **Android Application** implementing concepts of cryptography, data transfer on wireless networks, user monitoring, storing mass-data entries and event scheduling etc using Kotlin/Java.
- Worked and Experienced with IOTs Arduino, NodeMcu, RASP Pi.
- Developed Windows GUI **Application using Java Swing** and AWT.
- Worked on projects using Microsoft's Latest GUI Framework: WinUi 3 and .Net
- Maintained version control using Github
- Developed a Voice Assistant using python and Google TTS **API in PYTHON programming** language.
- Developed A Face Tracker, and **Hand Guester Control using OpenCV** in python language

My short- term goal is to get a job in a reputed company and improve my skill and my long-term goal is to achieve a good position in my area of work. My ethic is I never neglect any opportunity for my improvement.

> **Total Work Experience: 2+ Years Availability: Full Time / Part time**

DOMAIN EXPERTISE/ **PROFICIENCY**

Android Development Kotlin Java **PYTHON** C# **PostgreSQL**

TESTIMONIAL

Abdullah Omer has built apps for me which are no doubt stable and best in class for me.

- Nilesh Hadalgi

COMPLEMENTARY SKILLS

GITHUB / Abdx79 **STACK OVERFLOW** .NET FRAMEWORK

CONTACTS Abdx79.com Xmer79@gmail.com in **LinkedIn Profile (Link) Google Play Profile (Link)** Google Play

Mohammed Abdullah **Omer**

Software Developer

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Published App on Google Play Store (July 2023)
 - Built android app 'Save it' that allows users to label and save content.
 - · It has Modern UI
 - Memory efficient with cache handling and pagination
 - Simple and clear UX

ANDROID KOTLIN SQL

- Freelancing (May 2019 to December 2022)
 - · Built an android app for a Youtuber. App creates, handles, and automatically starts meetings on schedule time.
 - Built and Typing Speed Analyzer for instagrammer
 - Built staff managing app
 - and more

PYTHON ANDROID KOTLIN

- Freelancing (May 2018 to May 2019)
 - Built IOT apps
 - Built Sensors controlled wheelchair
 - Distance calculator using ultrasonic sensors
 - and more

ANDROID KOTLIN SENSORS C++

MAJOR PROJECTS

Ai Model and Wumpus World Game (June December 2023)

- Dynamic Wumpus World game.
- Ai Model that learns and plays the game

Ai/ML **PYTHON PyGame**

WiFi Ecosystem (July 2022 to December 2022)

This ecosystem among the connected devises will allow swift file Transfer, Over The Air (OTA) controls, Notifications Sync etc.

.NET FRAMEWORK

C#

ANDROID KOTLIN WEB SOCKETS

Staff Management App (March 2022 to May 2022)

This is an windows application built on Microsoft's latest Graphical User Interface (GUI) i.e Win Ui 3, allows the user to see, manage, Administrate the staff for optimal performance and reliable task Controls, Notifications Sync etc.

.NET FRAMEWORK C#

Notifications Manager (August 2021 to November 2021)

- This is an Android application which allows a user to Save all the upcoming notifications.
- · Create a custom event which is triggered when certain actions are
- Detected. · Broadcast notifications over headphones while driving or ridding.
- **ANDROID DATA STRUCTURES KOTLIN**

Its a better version of Notifications Manager with

Notifications Manager 2.0 (January 2022 to April 2022)

- a. Better User Interface
- b. Better fail safe methods c. Robust data storing algorithms
- d. User authentication for privacy
- e. Fast by Implementing paging algorithms

DATA STRUCTURES ANDROID KOTLIN

ACHIVEMENTS

Hackathon Winner MJCET 2023 Hackathon Winner NSAKCET 2023

Android Developer Badge, LinkedIn

APPLICATIONS & TOOLS KNOWN

Python Programmer Badge, LinkedIn



Android













EDUCATION

- Diploma In Computer Science from Telangana State Board Of Technical Education & Training in 2021. Bachelor of Engineering from Osmania University in Computer
- Science Engineering, Currently pursuing last year (4th year).

INTERESTS









